# Pooja M Ambali

pujaambli@gmail.com \$8867841824 in www.linkedin.com/in/pooja-m-ambali-891292148

#### **Profile**

Meticulous developer with 3 years of work experience in Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Image Processing, Machine Learning, and Model Deployment. Keen interest in solving Video Analytics Solutions and have been entrusted upon taking the responsibilities.

# **Professional Experience**

#### 10/2020 - present

# **Senior Al Engineer,** *Tata Elxsi*

- Worked extensively with Deep Neural Networks (DNN), Convolution Neural Network (CNN), Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) architectures to develop various Image and Video Analytics solutions.
- Identified client needs and suggested appropriate services to enhance user
- Worked on designing models in ML/DL as per requirements of the problem statement.
- Worked on model optimization, fine-tuning, and evaluation.
- Experience in Deploying AI Models on AWS using SQS, S3, EC2 Instance, ECR, Lambda Functions.

#### 08/2018 - 09/2020

# **Al Engineer,** Tata Elxsi

- Experience in working on Object Detection algorithms (FasterR-CNN, YOLO), Image Classification, and Semantic Segmentation.
- Good understanding of Neural Network Architecture and Data Preparation.
- Experience in various techniques like Data Gathering, Data Visualization, Data Cleaning, Data Preprocessing, Data Augmentation, and Data Post-processing.
- Experience in running AI models with celery.
- Hands-on Experience in working with Dockers, GPU environments.

#### **Skills**

#### **Programming languages**

C, Python

**Deep Learning Frameworks** 

Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch

#### **Computer Vision**

**Database** MongoDB

# **Cloud Platform AWS**

#### **Tools and Others**

**Machine Learning** 

Jupyter Lab, Sublime, Jira, Git, Docker

#### **Python Libraries**

OpenCV, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Celery, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn, PIL

#### **Certifications and Awards**

- Deep Learning Specialization Coursera.
- Awarded as a best project under the Innovative Project for the year 2021 (Innov@TE)

#### **Patents**

"Method and System for Imprinting Source Identifier for Identifying Unauthorised and Pirated Media Content"

# **Projects**

# • Implementation of Covert Watermarking Solution.

The solution helps in determining unauthorized and pirated video copies.

## • Face Similarity Check and Model Deployment in AWS.

This solution is responsible for getting the Face Similarity score between two persons.

## • Ad Analytics for placing the approriate ads.

Gathering the useful information from the videos analysis to place appropriate ads.

# • Binge Watch Feature Implementation.

This feature helps in determining the skip-intro start time, skip-intro end time, and end credits start time of the video.

## Video Analytics

The solution helps in determining the violent scenes in the video using Blood Gore Classifier and Object Detection.

#### **Education**

10/2020 – 10/2022	<b>Masters in Technology</b> , Birla Institute of Technology and Science (Work Integrated Learning Program 2nd Sem)
08/2014 - 06/2018	<b>Bachelor of Engineering</b> , Basaveshwar Engineering College. GPA - 8.67